https://optima-systems.co.uk/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy • Optima Systems
COVID-19 Update: We continue to provide the same service as before to all our customers. Read More
The Power of APL
What is APL?
1. Introduction & General Terms
Optima Systems Ltd is committed to protecting your personal information when you are using our website and to do so in accordance with the requirements of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).  We want our website to be safe and enjoyable. This Privacy Policy relates to our use of any personal information you provide to us via phone or text, by email, in letters or correspondence. It also relates to our use of any personal information you provide to us when you use this website.
This Privacy Policy explains the following:
what information Optima Systems Ltd may collect about you;
how Optima Systems Ltd will use information we collect about you;
when Optima Systems Ltd may use your details to contact you;
whether Optima Systems Ltd will disclose your details to anyone else;
your choices regarding the personal information you provide to us;
the use of cookies on Optima Systems Ltd website and how you can reject these cookies.
Optima Systems Ltd is committed to safeguarding your personal information. Whenever you provide such information, we are legally obliged to use your information in line with all laws concerning the protection of personal information, including the General Data Protection Regulation.
Optima Systems Ltd website may from time to time contain hyperlinks to websites owned and operated by third parties. These third-party websites have their own privacy policies, and are also likely to use cookies and we therefore urge you to review them. They will govern the use of personal information you submit, which may also be collected by cookies whilst visiting these websites. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of such third-party website and your use of such website is at your own risk.
2. Who are we?
Optima Systems Ltd is an IT Consultancy company offering bespoke software solutions.  In addition, we also provide network support and maintenance and web site design and maintenance.
When we refer to ‘’we’’ or ‘’our’’ or ‘’Optima Systems Ltd’’ we are referring to Optima Systems Ltd.
3. What information will Optima Systems Ltd collect about me?
By submitting your details, you enable Optima Systems Ltd (and where applicable its contractors) to provide you with the services, activities or online content you select.
Please note that sometimes we will require you to provide additional personal information. When we do this, we will provide further information as to why we are collecting your information and how we will use it.
Website usage information is collected using cookies (see section 12 below for details) and collects IP addresses (an IP address is a number that can uniquely identify a specific computer or other network device on the internet) from visitors to Optima Systems Ltd website.
4. How and when will Optima Systems Ltd use the information it collects about me?
Optima Systems Ltd will use your personal information for the following:
to contact you about a submission you have made via the a contact form on our website, including any content you provide;
to provide you with information about our services which you have requested;
to use IP addresses to identify the location of users, to block disruptive use, to establish the number of visits from different countries and to determine whether you are accessing the services from the UK or not;
to analyse and improve the services offered on the Optima Systems Ltd website;
Optima Systems Ltd may contact you:
in relation to any correspondence we receive from you or any comment or complaint you make about Optima Systems Ltd products or services;
for marketing purposes, where you have agreed to this (see section 6 below);
5. Will I be contacted for marketing purposes?
Optima Systems Ltd will only use your information for marketing purposes, or to promote new services, activities or online content where you have submitted a contact form on our website.
6. Will Optima Systems Ltd share my personal information with anyone else?
We will keep your information confidential except where disclosure is required or permitted by law (for example to government bodies and law enforcement agencies) or as described in section 8 below. Your information will be stored securely on our servers which are protected by industry standard encryption. We will only use your information within Optima Systems Ltd.
We will not share your information with other companies. We will not sell your information to other companies.
7. Offensive or inappropriate content on Optima Systems Ltd website
If you post or send offensive, inappropriate or objectionable content anywhere on or to Optima Systems Ltd website or otherwise engage in any disruptive behaviour on any Optima Systems Ltd service, Optima Systems Ltd may use your personal information to stop such behaviour.
Where Optima Systems Ltd reasonably believes that you are or may be in breach of any applicable laws (e.g. because content you have posted may be defamatory), Optima Systems Ltd may use your personal information to inform relevant third parties such as your employer, school email/internet provider or law enforcement agencies about the content and your behaviour.
8. What if I am a user aged 16 or under?
If you are aged 16 or under, please get your parent/guardian's permission before you provide any personal information to Optima Systems Ltd. Users without this consent are not allowed to provide us with personal information.
9. How long will Optima Systems Ltd keep my personal information?
We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant activity, or as long as is set out in any relevant contract you hold with Optima Systems Ltd. Personal data held is subject to regular review. Data about you is only stored in the UK. We will delete personal data if it has not been used or there has been no contact for six years.
10. Can I find out what personal information Optima Systems Ltd holds about me?
Under the General Data Protection Regulation, you have the right to request a copy of the personal information Optima Systems Ltd holds about you and to have any inaccuracies corrected. We will use reasonable efforts to supply, correct or delete personal information about you on our files. Optima Systems Ltd will make no charge for any valid subject data request.
Please address requests and questions about this or any other question about this Privacy Policy to the Data Protection Controller, Optima Systems Ltd, Optima House, Spindle Way, Crawley, West Sussex RH10 1TT. (Email: gdpr@optima-systems.co.uk).
Subject data access requests will be dealt with within one month from receipt of the request.
11. What if I am accessing Optima Systems Ltd website outside the UK?
Optima Systems Ltd website is published in the UK by Optima Systems Ltd as Optima-systems.co.uk. All personal information submitted by users outside the UK to Optima Systems Ltd will be processed in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
12. Cookies Policy - Information Optima Systems Ltd collects from you
Summary
Cookies are text files placed on your computer to collect standard internet log information and visitor behaviour information. This information is used to track visitor use of the website and to compile statistical reports on website activity.
For further information visit www.aboutcookies.org or www.allaboutcookies.org.
You can set your browser not to accept cookies and the above websites tell you how to remove cookies from your browser. However, in a few cases some of our website features may not function as a result.
In Detail
a. What is a cookie?
A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes a unique identifier that is sent to your computer, tablet or mobile phone (referred to here as a "device") browser from a website's computer and is stored on your device's hard drive. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser's preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a website to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by another website. Many websites do this whenever a user visits their website to track online traffic flows.
During any visit to Optima Systems Ltd website, the pages you see, along with a cookie, are downloaded to your device. This enables us to find out whether the device (and probably its user) has visited the website before. This is done on a repeat visit by checking to see, and finding, the cookie left there on the last visit.
b. How does Optima Systems Ltd website use cookies?
Information supplied by cookies can help us to analyse the profile of our visitors and help us to provide you with a better user experience. Optima Systems Ltd uses this type of information to help improve the services it provides to its users. All third parties are strictly required not to use any information for their own business or other purposes (see section 6 above).
c. Third Party Cookies in embedded content on Optima Systems Ltd pages
Please note that during your visits to Optima Systems Ltd website you may notice some cookies that are not related to Optima Systems Ltd or Optima Systems Ltd.’s contractors. When you visit a page with content embedded from, for example, YouTube you may be presented with cookies from these websites. Optima Systems Ltd does not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the third-party website for more information about these.
Types of cookies
First party cookies
First party (or standard) cookies are set by the website, you are visiting, and they can only be read by that site.
Third party cookies
Third party cookies are set by a different organisation to the owner of the website you are visiting. For example, the website might use a third-party analytics company who will set their own cookie to perform this service. The website you are visiting may also contain content embedded from, for example YouTube and these sites may set their own cookies.
Session cookies
Session Cookies are stored only temporarily during a browsing session and are deleted from the user’s device when the browser is closed.
Persistent cookies
This type of cookie is saved on your computer for a fixed period (usually a year or longer) and is not deleted when the browser is closed. Persistent cookies are used where we need to know who you are for more than one browsing session.
Flash cookies
Optima Systems Ltd does not use this type of cookie. However, many websites use Adobe Flash Player to deliver video and game content to their users. Adobe utilise their own cookies, which are not manageable through your browser settings but are used by the Flash Player for similar purposes, such as storing preferences or tracking users.
Flash Cookies work in a different way to web browser cookies (the cookie types listed above are all set via your browser); rather than having individual cookies for particular jobs, a website is restricted to storing all data in one cookie. You can control how much data can be stored in that cookie, but you cannot choose what type of information can be stored.
13. Do Not Track (DNT) browser setting
DNT is a feature offered by some browsers which, when enabled, sends a signal to a website to request that your browsing is not tracked, such as by third party ad networks, social networks and analytic companies. This website does not currently respond to DNT requests.
14. Changes to Optima Systems Ltd's Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time, so you may wish to check it each time you submit personal information to Optima Systems Ltd. The date of the most recent revisions will appear on this page. If you do not agree to these changes, please do not continue to use the Optima Systems Ltd website to submit personal information to Optima Systems Ltd. If material changes are made to the Privacy Policy, we will notify you by placing a prominent notice on the website.
Last updated: March 2018
Any Questions?
Please use the form below to get in touch with us. Alternatively call 01293 562 700 during office hours!
Your name *
Your phone number *
Your email address *
Your Message / Enquiry
By submitting this form you are agreeing to the conditions laid out in our Privacy Policy and also understand that you are authorising Optima Systems to contact you for the purposes that you have described in your message.
I accept!
t:
01293 562 700
e: support@optima-systems.co.uk
Mon - Fri, 8:00am - 5:30pm
Accounts & Billing
t:
What is APL?
© 1990 - 2020 Optima Systems Ltd. All Rights Reserved. Registered Company in England & Wales no: 247 1123 | VAT No: 573 9032 29
Website made in-house!
What is APL?
We use cookies to improve user experience and analyse traffic on our website. Click here for more information. No personal info is stored. Got it
